American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIa. 1743-1806 APS.Archives.IIa APS.Archives.IIa
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - List of subscribers to A.P.S. Transactions, April 18, 1788; 7 1/2" x 12 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    o.s., I, Philadelphia, 1 p. D.S. Of great value. Contains autographs of Benjamin Franklin, John Vaughan, David Rittenhouse, Caspar Wistar, and others.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., April 18, 1788; 8 1/4" x 13"; Voigt, Henry
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p. and add. and end. drawings Addressed also to Benjamin Franklin. Lays before them some of his ideas of creating steam.
  - W[illia]m Lewis to [the American Philosophical Society, May 1, 1788; 8 1/4" x 13 1/4"; Lewis, William
    Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. A.D.S. Legal opinion condemning the steps of Philosophical Hall as a nuisance. See Minutes, July 18, 1788, in Pro., XXII,pt. 3, 162.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 2, 1788; 13x8; Rumsey, James, 1743?-1792
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Trade, navigation, etc., no. 8.) Asks for copy of his machine for cleansing chimneys. See J.Rumsey. Description of a machine for cleansing chimneys; 1786.
  - Improved method of finding longitude at sea, June 19, 1788; 9-1/2x8; Byrnes, Daniel
    D.S. 1p. and end. (see Ms. Comm.to APS. Math and Astronomy, vol. 1, no. 20.) Enclosed originally in letter from Byrnes to Franklin; Aug. 15, 1788. FILM 54-63 FRAME 52
  - Letter to Dr. Franklin, Rittenhouse, John Vaughan, July 17, 1788; 7 1/4" x 9"; Vaughan, Benjamin, 1751-1835
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Transmits two thermometers presented to the A.P.S. by Mr. Six, the inventor.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin], July 26, 1788; 7x9-1/2; Arthaud, Charles
    Cap-François], A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Sends his treatise on Epizootia to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, Aug. 15, 1788; 8x8; Byrnes, Daniel
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Enc. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Math and Astronomy, vol. 1, no. 19.) New quadrant. For enclosure, see Byrnes: improved method...longitude at sea; June 19,1788. FILM 54-63 FRAME 52
  - Description of a wheelboat proposed to facilitate the navigation of the North American rivers., 1788 September 19
    Description of a wheel boat that "may be worked alternately with and hands and feet.., [that] will give a force from 3 to 6 times greater, than that of the arms moving an oar." Read before the 0society on September 19, 1788.
  - Letter to the president and members of the A.P.S., Sept. 19, 1788; 8x12-1/2; Barbé-Marbois, Francois, marquis de, 1745-1837
    Port au Prince, L.S. 1p. and end. Presents to the A.P.S. a copy of his [Etatdes finances de St. Dominique]. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 164.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin ?], Sept. 21, 1788; 7 1/4" x 9"; Granchain de Sémerville, ca. 1741-1815
    Toulon, A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Acknowledges election to membership in the Society.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, Oct. 1, 1788; 12x7-1/2; Pleasants, James B.
    Montgomery County, A.L.S. 4p., end. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Natural philosophy, vol. 1, no.16.) Concerning balloons.
  - Letter to Dr. Franklin, Oct. 2, 1788; 7 3/4" x 10"; Bond, Phineas, 1749-1815
    Second Street, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Transmits books from Charles Dilly to the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, pres. of A.P.S, Oct. 22, 1788; 7 1/4" x 10"; Hazard, Ebenezer, 1744-1817
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Transmits to A.P.S. from Mr. Belknap of Boston, a copy of Swediaur's Observations on venereal complaints. Cf. minutes, Nov. 7,1788.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin ?], Nov. 21, 1788; 7" x 9"; Arthaud, Charles
    Cap [François], A.L.S. 1p. and end. In French. Donations for the [A.P.S.] Society, including a program of the Cercle des Philadelphes du Cap François.
  - The [American] Philosophical Society to William Johnson, November 22-June 23, 1788-1789; 5 3/8" x 8 1/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. D. Receipted by William Johnson, April 4, 1791. Receipted bill for £12.17.5, for miscellaneous work at Philosophical Hall.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, 1789 January 1; Foulke, John, 1757-1796
    Letter of resignation from the office of Corresponding Secretary of the A.P.S..
  - The [American] Philosophical Society to McCulloh and Peterson, January 28, April 19, 1789; 4 3/4" x 8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D. Unsigned. Bill for £37.4.2 1/2, for lumber used in Philosophical Hall.
  - [American Philosophical Society] to Daniel Richards, January 26-April 7, 1789; 8 1/4" x 11 7/8"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., 1 p. and endorsement. D. Receipted by Daniel Richards, Receipted bill for £78.1.1, for lumber used in Philosophical Hall.
  - Recommendation of Petrus Camper of Friesland as a member of the A.P.S., 1789; 6-1/2x4; Morgan, John, 1735-1789
    [ca.]. D.S. 1p. At a former meeting B.Franklin and S.Vaughan proposed the above gentleman.
  - List of his mechanical inventions, 1789; 12-1/2x7-1/2; Schultz, William
    A.D.S. 2p.,end. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery Eng., etc., no.8.) Includes lightning rod.
  - Trustees of University of Pennsylvania to Jones, April 22-May 26, 1789; 6 3/4" x 8 3/8"; University of Pennsylvania
    Clark and Cresson, Dr., [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S. Bill for £75.1.11, for lumber used in Philosophical Hall.
  - Trustees of University of Pennsylvania to Jones, May 29-June 27, 1789; 6 3/4" x 6 3/8"; University of Pennsylvania
    Clark and Cresson, Dr., [Philadelphia], 1 p. D. Unsigned. Bill for £11.3.1, for lumber used in Philosophical Hall.
  - John Foulke to Benj[ami]n Franklin, January 1, 1789; 7 1/2" x 9 1/4"; Foulke, John
    President of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Letter of resignation from the office of corresponding secretary of the A.P.S.
  - Letter to David Rittenhouse, Jan. 3, 1789; 9x7-1/2; Humphreys, Joshua, 1751-1838
    Southwark, A.L.S. 2p.and add.and end. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 5.) Concerning the regulation of a pendulum Cf. Minutes, p.167.
  - Letter to Dr. Franklin, pres. of A.P.S., Jan. 16, 1789; 7 3/4" x 12 1/2"; Aitken, Robert, 1735-1802
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Relative to reprinting of Vol.1 of the Transactions.
  - Sam[uel] Magaw to John Vaughan, January 26, 1789; 9 1/2" x 15 1/4"; Magaw, Samuel, 1735-1812
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. A.D.S. List of members of the American Philosophical Society chosen in January and July, 1787.
  - List of proposed, and elected, members, with signatures of men who recommended them, Jan., [1789]; 8-1/4x6-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: B.Franklin. et. at. 1p.and end. FILM 54-64 FRAME 228, FILM 403 FRAME 18
  - Extract from the minutes of the directors of the Library Company of Philadelphia, February 5, 1789; 9 3/4" x 15 1/2"; Library Company of Philadelphia
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D. Copy. Unsigned. Refusal of Library company to use A.P.S. building for safe keeping of its books. Entire extract concerns B. Franklin's letter.
  - Letter to Hector St. Jean de Crevecoeur, Feb. 10, 1789; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, Photostat of L.S: James Hutchinson, Jn. Vaughan, secretaries. 1p. Notifies him that he has been elected to membership in the Society. From film in L.C. Original in volume of letters to St. John de Crevecoaur owned by M. Louis St. John de Crevecoeur, La Plagne, Montesquiou-sur Losse (Gers), France.
  - Diego de Gardoqui to James Hutchinson and John Vaughan, New York, February 13, 1789; 8" x 9 13/16"; Gardoqui y Arriquibar, Diego, 1735-1798
    2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. (In Spanish, with English translation.) Acknowledges the receipt of his certificate of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Benj[ami]n Rittenhouse to John Vaughan and James Hutchinson, February 14, 1789; 7 7/8" x 12 3/4"; Rittenhouse, Benjamin F.
    1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of certificate of membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, Feb. 16, 1789; 9x7-1/2; Humphreys, Joshua, 1751-1838
    Southark, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Mech., Machinery, Engineering, etc. no.6.) Concerning scale beams.
  - John Cox to James Hutchinson and John Vaughan, Bloomsbury, February 17, 1789; 7 3/8" x 9 1/8"; Cox, John, 1731-1793
    2 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of certificate of membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Walter Minto to J[ames] Hutchinson and J[ohn] Vaughan, February 19, 1789; 7 1/2" x 9 1/16"; Minto, Walter, 1753-1796
    Princeton, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of certificate of membership in the American Philosophical Society. Printed: APS Library Bulletin for 1950,p.292.
  - David Brearley to James Hutchinson and John Vaughan, February 23, 1789; 7 9/16" x 9 1/8"; Brearly, David, 1745-1790
    Trenton, 1 p. and endorsement. acknowledges receipt of certificate of membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Letter to John Foulke, Feb. 27, 1789; 13x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    L. 1p.and end. Thanks for his oration "On the State, Stages and Chances of the human constitution and life, and particularly supporting the chances of Longevity in North America" See: Minutes, p.170.
  - Peter S. DuPonceau to William Barton, March 2, 1789; 6 1/2" x 8 1/4"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Donates a number of books, mostly in foreign languages, to the A.P.S. List enclosed.
  - List of books presented to the American Philosophical Society by... [Philadelphia,]., March 2, 1789; 8 1/8" x 13"; Du Ponceau, Peter Stephen, 1760-1844
    1 p. and endorsement. D. Enclosed in: P. S. DuPonceau to William Barton, March 2, 1789. Read, March 6, 1789. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 170.
  - Letter to John Vaughan, March 6, 1789; 8x6; Clifford, Thomas
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. Wishes payment for materials and work done on Philosophical Hall.
  - Letter to Dr. Franklin, pres. of A.P.S., March 11, 1789; 8" x 13"; Aitken, Robert, 1735-1802
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add. and end. Relative to reprinting the first volume of the Society's Transactions; mentions Mr. Rittenhouse.
  - Nicholas Collin to Benjamin Franklin, March 20, 1789; 7 1/2" x 9 3/16"; Collin, Nicholas, 1746-1831
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Being prevented from delivering a discourse this evening, hopes "to perform the engagement this day two weeks."
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, March 21, 1789; 12-1/2x8; Churchman, John, 1753-1805
    A.L.S. 2p., end. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Math and Astronomy, vol. 1, no. 21.) Concerning a voyage to locate the northern magnetic pole. FILM54-62 FRAME53
  - St. John de Crevecoeur to James Hutchinson and others, April 1, 1789; 7 3/4" x 9 3/4"; St. John de Crèvecoeur, J. Hector, 1735-1813
    New York, 2 pp., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - Edward Pole to John Vaughan, April 1, 1789; 8 1/4" x 9 3/4"; Pole, Edward
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents model of silk reeling machine to A.P.S. See Minutes, April 3, 1789, in Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 172.
  - Lease issued to the University of Pennsylvania for rental of a portion of the Society's hall, April 3, 1789; 9" x 15"; American Philosophical Society
    D. 2p. and end. Attest: Sam. Magaw, sec. Jn. Vaughan, sec. Seal
  - Lease of a portion of Philosophical Hall to the University of Pennsylvania, April 3, 1789; 15x9-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, D. 2p.and end. Seal. Attest: Edward Fox, Secy.
  - W[illia]m Paterson to John Vaughan and James Hutchinson, April 8, 1789; 7 11/16" x 9 3/4"; Paterson, William, 1745-1806
    New York, 1 p. address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges receipt of certificate of membership in the American Philosophical Society.
  - List of proposed members, and men who recommended them, April 17, 1789; 13x8-1/4; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: B.Franklin, et al. 1p. For statement of election, see: Minutes p. 172.
  - Letter to [the A.P.S.], April 23, 1789; 13x9; Hüpsch-Lontzen, Johann Wilhelm Carl Adolph von Honvlez-Ardenn, Freiherr von, 1730?-1805
    Cologne, A.L.S. 4p.,end. Enc. In French. Forwards broadside. Would like to correspond on natural history. For enclosure see: Hupsch. Monsieur. Le Proposition...; April 24, 1789.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, Philadelphia, April 24, 1789; 10x7-1/2; Grier, Arthur
    Reading, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Note in B. Franklin's hand in French on add.page. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Math and Astronomy, vol. 1, no.22.) Concerning longitude.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, May 1, 1789; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Clifford, Thomas
    Philadelphia, L.S. 1p.,end. and add.,end. Asks that the APS pay for work and materials used on the construction of Philosophical Hall.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, May 14, 1789; 7 1/2" x 9"; Aitken, Robert, 1735-1802
    Philadelphia A.L.S. 1p. and add. and end. Relative to the reprinting of the first volume of the Transactions.
  - Francis Gardoqui to James Hutchinson and J[oh]n Vaughan, May 19, 1789; 7 7/16" x 9 1/16"; Gardoqui, Francis
    Rome, 1 p., address and endorsements. A.L.S. Acknowledges the receipt of his certificate of membership in the A.P.S.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, May 22, 1789; 13x8; Stroebel, John Christopher
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Medicine, anatomy & physiology, no. 4.) Concerning an articel on animal heat.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, Philadelphia, May 29, 1789; 12x8; Grier, Arthur
    Reading, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Math and Astronomy, vol.1, no. 25.) Concerning longitude.
  - The trustees of the University [of Pennsylvania] to James Bringhurst and Sons, June 4, 1789; 8 3/8" x 13 1/8"; University of Pennsylvania
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 5pp. and endorsement. D.S. Bill for £160.6.9, for miscellaneous materials for Philosophical Hall.
  - P(eter) Legaux to (John) Vaug(h)an, June 9, 1789; 7 1/2" X 9 1/8"; Legaux, Peter, 1748-1827
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Springmill, 2 pp. A.L.S. (In French).
  - Winthrop Sargent to [Benjamin] Franklin, June 25, 1789; 7 11/16" x 12 5/8"; Sargent, Winthrop, 1753-1820
    Marietta, 2 pp. and endorsements. A.L.S. Forwards his meteorological observations to the A.P.S. Acknowledges his election to membership therein.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, Philadelphia, July 4, 1789; 15x9-1/2; Brisbane, James
    A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. (see Ms.Comm.to APS. Math and Astronomy, vol. 1, no. 26.) Concerning longitude. FILM54-63 FRAME57
  - The [American] Philosophical Society to Joseph Ogilby, July 6, 1789; 6 1/2" x 15 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S. Bill for carpentry work at Philosophical Hall, £260.8.6.
  - Letter to the president and members of the A.P.S., July 20, 1789; 7-1/2x9; Huiberts, J.
    Amst[erdam], A.L.S. 2p. and end. Encloses letter from Baron von Hupsch.
  - James Bringhurst to the committee [of the A.P.S.] for finishing the Hall and the Trustees of the University [of Pennsylvania], July 28, 1789; 8 3/8" x 13 1/8"; Bringhurst, James, d. 1810
    Philadelphia, 2 pp. A.L.S. Regarding type and cost of glass for Philosophical Hall.
  - Letter to James Hutchinson, acting for the Trustees of the University, Aug. 4, 1789; 9x7-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, L.S. 1p.and add. Concerning Bringhurst's account with the society for Philosophical Hall.
  - Letter to Benjamin Franklin, Sept. 8, 1789; 8" x 13 1/4"; Redick, David
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Sends by Absolom Baird certain natural productions. Formation of coal. See APS Minutes, Oct. 2,1789.
  - Letter to J [oh]n Vaughan, Sept. 12, 1789; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Heinitz, Friedrich Anton, Freiherr von, 1725-1802
    Berlin, L.S. 1p.and end. In French. Acknowledges membership in the APS.
  - Jam(e)s Gardoqui to John Vaughan, September 24, 1789; 7 5/8" x 9 7/8"; Gardoqui, James
    New York, 1p. address and endorsement. A.L.S. Inquires whether "the Spanish Ladies" have been elected members of A.P.S.; requests that their certificates be sent to him.
  - Letter to [the A.P.S.], Nov. 15, 1789; 12-1/2x8; Vautravers, Jean-Rodolphe, b. 1723
    Hamburg, A.L.S. 6p.,end. Enc. Sends questions for the premiums offered by the Oeconomical society of Hamburg. Refers to his friendship with Franklin.
  - Concerning how to cause a mill to go by bellows, and how to raise water above the level, Nov. 20, 1789; 13x8; Lewis, Alexander
    A.D.S. 1p.and add. (see Ms. comm.to the APS. Mechanics, machinery, eng., etc., no. 7.) Cf. Minutes, p.177.
  - Account of an instrument to discover the distance of an object, Nov. 20, 1789; 9x7-1/2; Lewis, Alexander
    A.D.S. 1p.and end. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Natural philosophy, vol. 1, no. 18.) Cf. Minutes, p.177.
  - Concerning how to cause a mill to go by bellows, and how to raise water above the level, Nov. 20, 1789; 13x8; Lewis, Alexander
    A.D.S. 1p.and add. (see Ms. Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 7.) Cf. Minutes, p.177.
  - Baron de Heynitz to J[oh]n Vaughan, Corresponding Secretary of the A.P.S., November 22, 1789; 7 3/8" x 9 1/4"; de Heynitz, Baron
    Berlin, 1 p. and endorsement. L.S. (In French.) Forwards to the A.P.S.: Memoirs of the Academy of Arts and Manufactures [of Berlin].
  - Report of committee on Franklin's new theory of the earth and Collin's enquiry as to the proper objects of philosophy in the U.S., Dec. 11, 1789; 12x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.with initials: S[amuel] M[agaw]. 2p. and end.
  - Letter to [Benjamin] Franklin, Dec. 18, 1789; 9x7-1/2; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Presents West Indian objects to the Society from his brother, Samuel. On same sheet is letter from Samuel to J. Vaughan; [1789].
  - Accounts of the A.P.S., March 31, Aug. 3, 1789, 1791; 8x13; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    D. 4p. Refers to B.Franklin.
  - The [American] Philosophical Society to the trustees of the University [of Pennsylvania), May 29, January 19, 1789, 1792; 7 5/8" x 9"; American Philosophical Society
    Dr., Philadelphia, 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Edward Fox. Statement of accounts with reference to building of Philosophical Hall.
  - The University [of Pennsylvania] to Jno. Pinkerton and Son, June 1-April 20, 1789-1790; 8 1/4" x 13 1/2"; University of Pennsylvania
    Dr., [Philadelphia], 2 pp. and endorsement. D.S. Receipted by J[oh]n Pinkerton & Son, September 14, 1791. Receipted bill for £11.1.9, for hardware used in building Philosophical Hall.
  - Account with John Vaughan, treasurer, March 31- March 4, 1789-1797; 13x8; American Philosophical Society
    D. 4p.
  - Communication of which no account has been published [before]., , 1790; 12x7-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    D. 2p., end. Mentions B.Franklin.
  - Selenotopographical fragments, July, 1790; 13x8; Fleckeisen, Carl Gottfried
    Helmstädt, D.S. 5p. (see Ms.comm.to the APS. Math. and astronomy, vol. 1, no. 28.) Advertisement. Cf. Minutes, p.188.
  - Lease of cellars under Philosophical Hall to John Vaughan for period of ten years, Jan. 1, 1790; 9x14-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, 3pp. and endorsement. D.S.: Dav[i]d Rittenhouse; witnessed by W[illiam] Barton; approved by Rich[ard] Bache for B.Franklin's estate.
  - Dav[i]d Rittenhouse to [Robert] Patterson, January 21, 1790; 6 3/8" x 7 9/16"; Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796
    Secretary of the A.P.S., Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Acknowledges his election to the presidency of the American Philosophical Society. Refers to Dr. Franklin.
  - Report of committee upon by-law relative to the establishment of committees of correspondence, February 5, 1790; 7" x 11 3/4"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 1 p. and endorsement. D.S.: W[illia]m Smith, D[avid] Redick, William Findley. See Pro., XXII, pt. 3, 179.
  - Rob[er]t Aitken to Jonathan B. Smith, February 18, 1790; 8 1/4" x 13"; Aitken, Robert, 1735-1802
    Philadelphia, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Requests the A.P.S. to pay note it has owed him for three years, as its nonpayment is causing him serious trouble.
  - Tho[ma]s Pole to the American Philosophical Society, April 1, 1790; 7 1/2" x 9 7/8"; Pole, Thomas, 1753-1829
    London, 1 p., address and endorsement. A.L.S. Presents printing types to A.P.S., in the name of Edmund Fry. See Minutes, Feb. 4, 1791, in pro., XXII, pt. 3, 188.
  - Letter to Robert Barclay, April 5, 1790; 14x9-1/2; Fisher, Miers, 1748-1819
    Philadelphia, L. 4p.,end. Copy. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 9.) Concerning Rumsey and a steam boat.
  - Report of committee on treasurer's accounts., April 16, 1790; 7 7/8" x 13 1/8"; American Philosophical Society
    [Philadelphia], 2 pp. D. Unsigned. Probably copy. Extract from minutes for date indicated. Resolutions concerning commission allowed to the treasurer.
  - J[oh]n Vaughan to American Philos[ophical] Society, April 23, 1790; 7 1/2" x 9"; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, 4 pp. and endorsement. A.L.S. Inability to find tenant for cellars of Philosophical Hall. Offers to pay Society $250 for ten year's use thereof.
  - Letter to the A.P.S., April 23, 1790; 7-1/2x9; Vaughan, John, 1756-1841
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. Refers to paying interest on the B. Franklin bond.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Franklin], June 1, 1790; 9x7-1/4; Bataafsch Genootschap der Proefondervindelijke Wijsbegeerte (Rotterdam, Netherlands)
    Rotterdam, A.L.S.: Gerh.Gyst.ten Haaff, director... 2p.and end. Sends vol.9 of their Transactions; desires APS publications since vol.1
  - Receipt to John Vaughan for expenses for the American philosophical society, June 24, 1790; 2x7-1/2; Vaughan, Samuel, 1720-1802
    D.S. 1p.
  - List of subscribers to A.P.S. Transactions, o.s., June 25, 1790; 6 1/2" X 8 1/2"; American Philosophical Society
    III, Philadelphia, t.p., 4 pp. in bound blank book. D.S. Contains autographs of John Vaughan, Samuel Vaughan, Benjamin Smith Barton, David Rittenhouse, William Smith, and others.
  - Letter to ----, Sept. 30, 1790; 4x7-1/2; Bradford, William, 1719-1791
    Cantwells Bridge, L. Extract. 1p.and end. (see Ms.Comm.to the APS. Trade, navigation, etc., no. 9.) Concerning a giant radish. Cf. Minutes, p.184.
  - Concerning a ramming block, Oct. 13, 1790; 13x8; Kuhn, Ludwig Conrad
    Philadelphia, D.S. 1p.and end. (see Ms.Comm. to the APS. Mechanics, Machinery, Eng., etc., no. 10.) Cf. Minutes, p.184.
  - Rob[er]t Aitken to the American Philos[ophical] Society, November 24, 1790; 8" x 12 7/8"; Aitken, Robert, 1735-1802
    Philadelphia, 1 p. and endorsement. A.L.S. Proposals for printing A.P.S. Transactions, o.s., III.
  - Receipts to the American philosophical society for payments for work done on Philosophical Hall, Dec. 24, 29, 1790; 4x8; Symington & Burn
    Philadelphia, D.in hand of Samuel and John Vaughan, S. 1p., end. On same sheet as: S.Vaughan. Statement of monies due..Symington...;Dec. 6, 1787.
  - List of some books borrowed from the library, June 9, Dec. 16, 1790, 1791; 7x8; American Philosophical Society
    D.S.: B.S.Barton and W.Barton. 1p.
  - Report of the treasurer [to the A.P.S.], [1791?] [January 21?]; American Philosophical Society.
    Treasurer's report, including membership lists for 1787, 1789 and 1791. Mentioned bond to Benjamin Franklin. Unsigned.
  - The A.P.S.in account with Robert Aitken Philadelphia, Jan. 31, 1791; 7-1/2x9; American Philosophical Society